CAREER TARGET: Data Analyst | Machine Learning Software Engineer

Aspiring Data Analyst with a *Master's degree in logic-based computation*. Possesses an aptitude for data analytics, a *continuous improvement mentality*, and practical experience developing data science, machine learning, natural language processing, and information retrieval tools that translate unstructured data into meaningful information. Offers skills in customer service, communication and interpersonal dynamics, and collaborative teamwork, reinforced by 1+ years' combined experience in IT and service environments, including large corporations and franchises. *Poised to leverage* broad technical skills, diverse perspective, and drive to learn new technologies to solve complex business problems. *Open to relocation*. *Technical Competencies:*

OPERATING SYSTEMS: Linux, Windows

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, Haskell, SQL, HTML/CSS, LATEX; and exposure to C, JavaScript, and Lisp

APPLICATIONS: git, unixy CLI tools, VMware, SPSS, Adobe CS, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Education

Master of Science (**MS**), *Logic (Computation)*, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands (2016)

Thesis: "Readtable-Macro Transducer-Chain Parsing" (Learn more: dte.li/rmtc.pdf)

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Cognitive Science (Language) & Philosophy, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN (2011)

Key Skills & Attributes: Computer Science • Machine Learning Libraries • Collaborative Teamwork • Software Development • Verbal & Written Communication • Analytical & Quantitative Problem Solving • Data Mining & Data Analysis • Technical Troubleshooting • Exposure to Project Management • Automated Technology Solutions • Continuous Improvement

Relevant Experience

Career Orientation 2019 – Present

Left Navient to pursue full-time professional development and launch a job search in the data science field.

- Learned functional programming techniques and acquired knowledge of machine learning libraries through self-study.
- Grew experience using HTML, CSS, and web technologies by refining and maintaining personal website.

SIFT Engineer, CLINICAL ARCHITECTURE

2017 - 2018

Hired by the CEO to work with the semantic interpretation of free text (SIFT) natural language processing tool. Designed complex SIFT arrays capable of using advanced text analytics to identify, interpret, and analyze patterns, derive meaningful insights, simplify healthcare terminology governance, and enhance the quality and usability of clinical information.

- Rapidly **overcame initial SIFT learning curve** and proprietary software training to collaborate with small teams of Programmers and Data Scientists and support the design of complex text searches for medical documents.
- Created Python scripts and designed complex SIFT arrays to parse and align unstructured text within ICD-10, SNOMED-CT, and medical information catalogs to achieve correlation to established medical terminology targets and enable healthcare providers, systems, and integrated delivery networks to detect critical patient information.
- Acquired hands-on experience using **SQL** to map, model, and normalize large data volumes, draw meaningful conclusions, and strengthen clinical decision-making processes.

Additional Experience

Customer Care Representative, NAVIENT

2019 (4 months)

Fielded large volumes of daily inbound/outbound calls to answer questions involving financial arrangements and education loan repayment processes. **Boosted communication and problem-solving** skills by creating income-based repayment plans.

Delivery Driver, Domino's Pizza

2018 - 2019

Cashier, P&C Fresh 2017 – 2018

Strengthened customer service, time management, and planning and organization skills by supporting store logistics and operations on a part-time basis.